In an attempt to save Mizuha, Fushi decides to take on Funa's form.
And you thought that it worked by giving out these things?
Because I was using the knocker. I used it and I won.
Finally, Fushi returns home to his friends.
I don't... think that anyone is really happy.
In a lonely night, I ask for help.
Can I save myself?
The voice of the heart is ringing.
誰かが変わってくれたなら それで救われるのか
不滅のあなたへ叫びたい 夢動く代わりに歌いたい
言葉と言葉を重ねて 秘密の彼方へ
あなたのハウルに grandfather ティナイ
水侙戦の未来
置く数が探し合った
Uh-huh.
Ow!
Hey, Goo Goo.
Oh, these injuries?
I did that plastic surgery thing I heard about.
Your mask was broken.
Uh, I stupidly fell down some stairs.
That's why my clothes are torn.
Me and Hyrule fell together.
Uh-huh.
Aw, gross.
Are you OK?
Did you injure your mouth?
Your dentures must have broken when you fell down the stairs
with me, right?
Why won't you tell me what really happened with you guys?
Are you all right?
Can you eat OK?
Don't worry, Fushi.
It was just one of those days.
Gramps and Aiko weren't home, and I was running errands,
so things cut a little out of hand.
Oh, ew.
I'm just super happy you're back home with us.
Hey, I should let Bon know you're back.
Oh, where is Bon anyway?
He had to go overseas on some sort of business trip.
Oh, Fushi, so you decided to come back at last.
Masar!
Look at everybody!
What's happened?
Huh?
What are you talking about?
There's nothing wrong with them.
No, but...
What's the matter?
Does it look like they've all changed since you ran away from home?
Mm-hmm.
They were all dragged into this new world without any warning or instruction.
Now they're trying to figure out how to live here.
That's pretty much it.
That's it?
That's why they're all sad?
Well, no one's dead, and they're doing better than they did before.
But it takes more than a new world to phase me.
Yeah, that's true.
You haven't changed at all, Masar.
That's because I can see clearly.
You should try taking a good look at your friends.
Uh-huh.
Hey, Gugu.
Check it out.
I just made a new mask for you.
Oh, thank you.
Sorry if it's not perfect.
About what happened.
I don't think it really broke after falling down some stairs.
Ouch!
Oh!
It's kind of rubbing against my wound.
Uh, sorry.
I know.
How about this?
It's really fluffy.
Ha!
What's this weird thing?
Huh?
Don't you remember?
That's the crayfish mask that Reen made for you.
Doesn't it take you back?
So Reen made this?
Mm-hmm.
But I just called it weird, and it turns out Reen made this!
She made it for me!
Mm-hmm.
Oh!
That's right.
She never had the chance to properly give it to you.
Hmm.
How's it look?
It looks real good!
Of course.
And Reen made it?
Mm-hmm.
Hmm.
I wish I could go back to Takunaha.
Uh...
Huh?
But...
Really?
Why, though?
You're... not... happy?
And...
Yaname?
It.
You first brought me back to life in Takunaha, right?
Well, Boozman's shop was still there.
And seeing it brought back some memories for me.
Ha!
I'm just messing.
Night.
Uh...
Maybe this place wasn't such a good choice for all of them after all.
Hey, Fushi!
I just received a message from Bon.
He says you should come check this out.
Hmm?
It's the International Weeding Federation.
They say they're gonna get rid of all the roots you've spread over the past 500 years.
The troublesome roots from Renrul have stopped growing, so now's the perfect time to get rid of them and clean up.
You're incorrect, sir.
Oh, it's fine.
The Great Tree is still alive.
Another Fushi fundamentalist.
You're just as stubborn as those roots.
Your ideology's a curse.
No!
I am not a curse!
And I'm not done yet!
The idea that the roots have stopped growing is a lie spread by the Church of Bennett.
No, right!
That's right.
I can keep going.
Hello, welcome!
I am at work, you know.
I'm here to find out what happened to you and Gugu.
I need to know.
It's like he said, we both fell down some stairs.
Oh, by the way, do you still have dentures?
Yeah, I still have my old ones with me.
Are you sure you don't want the newest ones?
Apparently, Gugu has been struggling to fit in at school ever since the very first day.
Why are you wearing that mask?
I have an injury.
Let me see!
Come on!
Take this mask off and show us!
Everyone at the school was fascinated by him.
They pestered him with their curiosity.
It's really a shame you and I aren't in the same grade together.
Maybe if I just show them my face, they'll be satisfied.
Oh, you're... normal?
Hey now, will you stop bullying the new kid?
I'm not, sir.
I'm just really fascinated about his strange mask.
Unfortunately, the rumors spread, which brought even more trouble.
What's up?
Are you afraid to show your face?
Don't you know that Ah-chan is in charge of this area?
You've got some nerve wandering over here without saying hi to him.
Who's Ah-chan?
What'd you say to me?!
Ouch!
Ah-chan, this guy's bad news!
So, you think you're a tough guy, is that right?
Hey, no! I haven't done anything!
Wannabe town mascot trying to take over my area!
Hey, just leave him alone!
What's that?
Huh?
You cracked it!
Look at what you've done to my mask!
You'll pay for that!
You do chill out!
You'll cause trouble for Kazumitsu!
Take this!
Are you kidding me?
What the?!
That didn't hurt!
Alrighty then.
I guess I'm getting mixed up in this as well.
Thanks, man.
No!
That kept happening to us for days.
Until eventually, we were detained by something called the police.
That's pretty much everything up to yesterday.
Gugu told me that he wanted to go back to Takunaha.
Sure, I know that place is really nice, but then...
Is living here really that bad?
Honestly, I don't know.
But either way, I'm going to be leaving that house within a year.
But why?!
There's a place for you to sleep and the food is good!
I just need something else.
I can't keep living like a kid forever.
If you count all the years I've lived, I'm actually older than Kazumitsu.
Well, I don't get it!
Is this place not good enough for anyone?!
What's wrong with it?!
School?!
Is it me?!
Hey, no, calm down.
I'm not leaving because I don't like it.
Actually, it's because this world that you've brought us into is so much fun.
I just want to go out there and explore some more of it.
Hey, where are you going?!
I can do more!
So, you weren't kidding about going back to Takunaha?
You seriously think Fushi's gonna send you off with a smile the way things are going right now?
I'm sure he already knows the truth.
I just didn't want him to see me all beat up like that after those fights.
Man, when he come home now?
Damn it, Fushi.
Just tell him everything that's pissing you off.
I don't want to be that kind of brother. No way.
Really?
I definitely prefer that kind of brother.
That's what I think.
Big brother ought to understand his little brother.
Hey, you guys. Have you seen Fushi?
No. He ain't here.
I told him how he got our injuries and he ran off. Like he had an idea.
I thought he came back to see you.
It's only us and the animals here at the moment.
Hey, everyone. Can any of you help me find Fushi?
Great. Let's go.
Hang on a minute. You mean they can understand us?
Don't worry. I'll find him.
I wonder if he went this way.
Oh, no. Look, it's another fight.
It's that masked boy again? Oh, dear.
Hold him!
Hey, Fushi! It's you, isn't it?
Cut it out!
Gugu? What are you doing here?
Will you quit talking? Get lost!
Run! This way!
Get back here, asshole!
What the hell are you doing?
Fighting those guys in my mask.
I'm sorry.
Hey, I know that face. Nando. I knew it. But why did you choose him?
Because he's the closest to you in build and muscle.
That's your reason?
Well, I wanted to find out how your life has been going lately. And as I was walking through town, those guys picked a fight with me.
It's just... anyone who hurts you, I'm sorry.
What the hell are you doing?
Fighting those guys in my mask?
I'm sorry.
Hey, I know that face. Nando. I knew it. But why did you choose him?
Because he's the closest to you in build and muscle.
That's your reason?
It's just... anyone who hurts you, hurts me. So, I got angry. I'm sorry, Gugu. It put you through so much pain, I never noticed.
Oh, I get it. You've been busy telling the soil for us potatoes so that we can grow properly.
Potatoes?
Never mind.
You really think Takunaha's better than this place?
I do.
When you brought me back to life, I saw Boozman's shop had barely changed. I was staring at it in awe when...
Hi there. The guy at the shop. He looked just like my brother. It was at that moment that I realized that my brother must have protected the place.
Excuse me. I'm... My name is Gugu. I'm a servant here. What's your name?
Listen up, Fushi. We need to have a talk about the future. If you're gonna live here, you have to learn how to do some work around this place.
I'm gonna work here too. What do you think?
It's really like it was back then.
Mhm.
Whoa, that mask!
Huh? Oh, this thing? Yeah, it's tacky. I just bought it.
No, I think it looks awesome. It'll be perfect for the festival. Please, why don't you come inside?
Oh, that's a painting of Reen Krop. She's the lady who used to run this shop.
Supposedly, she waited for her loved one to return so she never got married.
My ancestor had it painted many, many years ago.
Your ancestor?
Here, this is the brewery as it looked back then. It hasn't changed much, has it?
This man here was my ancestor. The guy in the middle there was the first owner. And next to him is Reen Krop again.
And this… is you.
Welcome home, Gugu.
My kid. It really is an impressive mask though, I must say. And you have the same physique. You're gonna be popular at the festival.
Huh?
Yeah, right! The festival, that's right! I've been looking forward to it!
Of course! And you should try to come by tomorrow too!
Huh?
I'm a granddad now…
Wonderful!
Me and my wife are trying for another…
Excuse me, what's this festival about again?
You're kidding, right? You're in that outfit and you still don't know?
Are you some sort of tourist?
Yeah, sort of…
This festival is to celebrate Gugu the Beast.
The Beast?
According to the legend, this is the sacred land where he was born. A long time ago, Takunaha was attacked by vicious monsters.
But the fire-breathing beast, Gugu, defeated them and saved the land. And so, every year, we're going to be able to do it.
I'm a granddad now.
Wonderful!
Me and my wife are trying for another…
Excuse me, what's this festival about again?
You're kidding, right? You're in that outfit and you still don't know?
Are you some sort of tourist?
Yeah, sort of.
This festival is to celebrate Gugu the Beast.
The Beast?
According to the legend, this is the sacred land where he was born. A long time ago, Takunaha was attacked by vicious monsters.
But the fire-breathing beast, Gugu, defeated them and saved the land.
And so, every year, we'd gather to celebrate and remember his heroic bravery.
Hey, look! Gugu's over there!
Gugu!
No one there wanted to attack me.
They all welcomed me.
It was as if my brother, and Bruceman, and Rin left it all behind as a gift to me.
I felt like I still had memories to make in Takunaha.
I wasn't done yet. My brother, my family, and… my home. I could see my future happening there.
However, there's no way I'm gonna leave behind my kid brother. I don't ever wanna hurt you.
Huh?
So, relax. It doesn't matter how many shitty people there are in this town. I'm not going to Takunaha.
Come on, what's up with that face? Did I say something weird? Sorry I'm a weak big brother getting all emotional about Takunaha.
That's not it. At all. I just realized there's more I need to do.
Fushii, look! What a weird dog.
Right then! I'll get my shit together too!
Good morning. Huh? Good morning.
You gotta do something, right?
Alright, take your seats. Good. The only absentee is Mizua because of her cold.
Oh, Fushii! Glad you could join us. Good for you!
Since you showed up, you could take the final exam later today.
Gugu might be going back to Takunaha. Hairou told me he'll leave home one day too.
And you? Will you be leaving as well?
Not yet, no. I haven't made any plans to leave.
Huh?
Are you busy studying?
No. I'm just reading because I enjoy it. I love it here. There are so many books to dive into.
I guess I might end up leaving if I find something really interesting.
Seems everyone's having a tough time. Do you think if I had made this place better and safer, nobody would have thought about leaving home?
You might be onto something there. So that's why you've been so anxious.
No matter how much of a paradise you turn this place into, you can't remove people's troubles, doubts, or anguish. After all, we're only human.
Huh?
I understand. You'd prefer a world without suffering, just like the Knockers do.
No! No way! I am nothing like the Knockers are! All I want is to make everyone's dreams come true! But instead... instead...
We'll make them come true ourselves.
Pain, anxiety, suffering, they always come to those who are chasing their dreams. Your dream is to grant all of our dreams, and that's why you're suffering. We're in the same boat.
Just look at me. When you brought me back to life in this young body, it came with all the problems and worries you'd expect it to come with. It's all such a pain.
Can I help? Can I solve those problems for you?
Hmm. Maybe you could solve them. But I don't want that. These problems are mine and mine alone. They're precious and important, so I'll keep them to myself.
You know, this third life is really quick. The days just go by so fast. I'm sure it's the same for the others. We're all searching for meaning in our own lives.
Yeah, but you don't need to be in such a rush, because I can keep you all alive forever!
Have you ever been curious about our lives?
Huh?
Have you ever wondered about our last thoughts before we died? Or how we planned to live from now on? Have you done that?
Uh, of course, yeah!
You have? Well, that's good then.
Hmm. You got ten more minutes.
Damn it.
You see, I told you that you shouldn't be working until your other arm is fully healed.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Aww.
Achoo!
Huh?
That's it. Focus, take a deep breath, hold it in, and go for it!
Yay!
I'm so proud! Well done!
What is this feeling? My heart is aching in my chest!
They were smiling. They seemed happy.
What's wrong with that? Why does my chest hurt? I've never felt this pain before!
The march I knew couldn't even write! That march couldn't even hold chopsticks!
Will she end up being like those kids at school someday?
Bye! See you later!
See you tomorrow!
We got so much homework today!
I know!
Let's study together!
Bye-bye, Fushi!
Hey, did you watch the show yesterday?
See ya!
Later...
Bye-bye! Fushi!
Ah, ah...
Bye-bye, Fushi!
See ya...
Later!
Bye-bye!
No.
Those who passed on and those who were left behind.
From the moment Fushi fell into his deep slumber to the final moments of his close friends,
Vaughn tells Fushi everything.
As the day of departure draws near.